(改编自加斯瑞斯克哈尔伯格的小说)
焰火之城
第一季第二集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
小萨
Sam?
Sam!
拜拜 老爸 2003年见
Bye, Pops. See you in 2003.
新年快乐 杨先生
Happy New Year, Mr. Yeung.
老天
Jesus.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
你爸似乎很讨厌我啊
It appears your dad hates me?
不 他讨厌的不是你
No. It's not you he hates,
只是新年前夜的缘故
it's just New Year's Eve.
唯一能与之相比的 就是他对国庆日的厌恶了
Matched only by his hatred for the Fourth of July.
好吧
Okay.
等等 我以为你说过他过去制作烟花
Wait, I thought you said he made fireworks though.
就好比...会计师讨厌报税季 他该喜欢新年前夜呀
Isn't that like-- It's like an accountant hating tax season.
他并非一直这样
Well, he wasn't always this way.
城里的好工作都被意大利人抢走了
The Italians get all the big jobs in the city,
他以前靠着小活收入也不错
and he used to do okay with the smaller gigs.
现在大家都在缩减开支
But now everyone's trying to cut corners.
这太糟糕了 这就像...
That sucks. That's like--
就像是炒掉圣诞老人只因为你找到了
It's like if you fired Santa Claus because you found someone who
能够用一半驯鹿送同样数量礼物的人
could deliver the same amount of presents using, like, half the reindeer.
对...没错
Yes. Yes. Yeah, totally.
如果圣诞老人 是个愤世嫉俗 胆固醇高的酒鬼
I mean, if Santa was a bitter alcoholic with high cholesterol.
但得承认 其实挺意外 圣诞老人不是这种人
But you got to admit, it's kind of surprising that he's not.
我觉得我爸内心是想被炒的
I think my dad secretly wanted to get fired.
他总是把我妈离开这事怪在自己身上
Like, he always blames himself for my mom leaving
现在他觉得自己应该受到惩罚
and now the world can't punish him enough, you know?
是
Yeah.
对 我担心我妈也会这样
Yeah, I worry about that happening to my mom.
如果带走她的哀伤 那还剩下什么
Like-- Like if you take away her grief, what's left?
除了她对我的操心 你懂吗
Besides her worrying about me. You know?
她不需要为你操心 因为有人在好好照顾你
Well, she doesn't have to worry about you because you're in good hands.
- 我们可以在屋顶看烟花 - 好的
- We can watch the fireworks from the roof. - All right.
- 当然 要添加几个加强道具 - 什么叫“加强道具”
- With a couple enhancements, of course. - What do you mean by "enhancements"?
查尔斯 我不知道你怎么样 但我已经受够了现实
I don't know about you, Charles, but I have had just about enough of reality.
好的 不行 这正是我妈操心的原因
Okay, no. That's exactly what my mom would worry about though.
好吧 你不需要事事都和她说
Okay. Well, you don't have to tell her everything.
而且你以前也吃过致幻蘑菇吧
Besides, you've shroomed before, right?
是 当然
Yeah, of course.
天啊 查尔斯 你永远不用对我说谎 好吗
Oh, my God. Charles, you never have to lie to me. Okay?
我绝不会评判你
I'm never gonna judge you.
在这个充满鬼话的世界上 有人会爱你 会离开你
In a world full of bullshit, where people are going to love you and leave you,
而你和我是彼此生命中唯一真实的存在
you and I will be the one true thing in each other's life.
好吗
Okay?
好的...
Yeah, okay.
好的
Okay.
我们走吧
Let's go.
出发喽
Here we go!
2003年
2003!
新年快乐
Happy New Year!
要命
Holy shit!
我知道 可不是嘛
I know, right?
你真知道
You do know?
- 我真知道 - 对 你知道的
- I do know. - Yeah, you do.
查尔斯
Charles...
我得告诉你一件事
I have to tell you something.
你可以告诉我任何事
Anything.
我需要水
I need water.
是 水
Yeah, water.
我们...我去帮你...水是个好主意
Let's-- I'll get you some-- Water's a great idea.
我们去买点水吧 这...
Let's get you some water. It's--
我要...我去去就回 好吗 留在这里别动
I'm gonna-- I'll be right back, okay? Stay here.
小萨
Sam?
- 搞什么  - 嗨...索尔
- What the fuck? - Hi. Hi, Sol.
你对她做了什么
What the fuck did you do to her?
- 什么 我 不...我没有... - 不...
- What, me? Me? No, no, no, no. I didn't-- - No, no, no. No.
- 查尔斯是朋友 - 她体内有什么
- Charles is a friend. - What's in her system?
披萨 热巧克力 她酒瓶里的东西和...
Pizza, hot chocolate, whatever was in her flask and then--
对 一些蘑...很多蘑菇
Yeah, some mushroo-- Well, a lot of mushrooms. I mean,
- 她比我多吃了一倍的量 - 好吧 嘿...
- she probably took twice as much as me. - Okay. Hey, hey.
别让她睡过去 好吗
Just keep her alert, okay?
楼下有淋浴间 让她去那里
There's a shower downstairs. Throw her in it.
好的
Okay, sure.
- 现在就去 - 是 准备好了吗
- Now! - Yeah. Ready?
新年快乐 索尔
Happy New Year, Sol.
好的...哟...
All right, all right, all right. Yo, yo.
马上就是午夜了
It's almost midnight.
哟 我说马上就是午夜了
Yo, I said it's almost midnight!
我只想感谢大家今晚过来
You know, I just wanted to thank everyone for coming.
和朋友们欢聚庆祝很重要
It's important for people to gather to celebrate.
没错
That's right.
我们就是这样创造仪式 形成社群的
You know, this is how we create ritual. Form community.
该死 革命就是这么开始的
Fuck, this is how we start a revolution.
来
There you go.
我们是邻居 朋友 艺术合作者
We are neighbors, friends, artistic collaborators...
- 好的... - 好的
- Okay-- - Okay.
这洗手间绝对不符合建造标准 但是 那大哥说你得清醒一下
This bathroom is definitely unpermitted, but big guy said to cool you down.
- 所以你进去吧 对 - 好 我需要坐下
- So let's get you in there, right. - Okay, I need to sit down.
- 什么 这里  - 我得坐下
- What? What, here? - I need to sit down.
好的 抱歉
Okay. Sorry.
来到这座城市 你一定是想创造好的作品
If you're in this city, it's 'cause you want to make shit.
因为你想做点大事
'Cause you wanna do shit.
你想出人头地
You wanna be the shit!
- 查尔斯 - 别担心 我来...
- Charles. - Don't worry. I got it, I got it.
对 有我在 别担心
Yeah, I got it. Don't worry about it.
- 小萨 我来 - 好的 谢谢
- Sam, I got it. - Okay, thank you.
来
Here.
你得从上面开始 是皮质的
You have to go from the top. They're leather.
- 什么  - 你得从上面一点开始拉
- What? - You need to pull from higher.
- 这里  - 对
- Like, here? - Yeah.
好的 我可以...抱歉
Okay. Well, I-- I can-- Sorry.
- 你能不能就抓住  - 抱歉 我行的
- Can you just grab on? - Sorry. I got it.
你闭上眼睛了
You're closing your eyes?
看着我...查尔斯
Look at me. Look at me, Charles.
- 好的 拉吧 - 什么
- Okay, just pull. - What?
我只想确定你觉得舒...没问题
I just want to make sure you're comf-- like, good.
好的 你就...
Okay, yeah, just--
好的
Okay.
这座城需要我们 如同我们需要它一样
This town needs us. Just as much as we need it.
说得没错
Tell 'em.
只要敢想 就能随心所欲 混蛋们
Now, if you can see it, you can be it, motherfuckers.
让2003年成为我们夺回 属于我们东西的一年
Now, let 2003 be the year that we take back what's ours.
让我们颠覆这座城市吧
Let's burn this city to the ground.
查尔斯 我脱不了上衣
Charles, I can't undo my top.
- 是...叫我吗  - 你能...对
- Is-- Is that me? - Can you-- Yeah.
好的
Okay.
就这里 对
Right here. Yeah.
我只是...
I just--
好的 可以了
Okay, I got it.
- 谢谢 - 不用
- Thank you. - Yeah.
十
Ten!
九
Nine!
五 四
Five! Four!
- 查尔斯 你在哪里  - 我在这 你还好吗
- Charles, where are you? - I'm here. Are you okay?
一
One!
新年快乐
Happy New Year!
我说过我会照顾你
I told you I would take care of you,
但似乎是你照顾我
but it looks like you're kind of the one taking care of me.
从没有这种经历
Never really had that before.
挺好的
It's nice.
你人真好 查理
You're really nice, Charlie.
我喜欢...照顾你
I like-- I like taking care of you.
小萨
Sam?
小萨 你说我可以告诉你任何事
Sam, you said I could tell you anything.
我觉得我得告诉你 我爱你
I think I need to tell you that I love you.
别干站着 我们得快点
Don't just stand there. We gotta hurry.
一 二...
One, two and--
(中央公园警局)
(圣玛丽教堂)
(这是你一直在寻找的迹象)
戴夫 是蕾根
Dave, it's Regan.
你听到这条留言后能不能立即回我电话
If you could call me back as soon as you get this message,
是关于我父亲
it's about my father.
比较急
It's time sensitive.
请录音 完成录音后
Please record your message. When you have finished recording,
您可以结束通话或按“1”进行其他选择
you may hang up or press one for more options.
艾伦
Alan,
我真的希望你没换号码 我想说 很抱歉打扰你
I really hope this is still your number and I would say, I'm sorry to bother you.
不过我显然不是在打扰你
Except I'm clearly not bothering you
因为你像我们所谓法务团队的 其他九个成员一样
since you, like the nine other members of our legal so-called team,
不接电话
are not answering the phone.
回我电话或让其他人打给我
Call me back or tell someone else to.
我需要帮助
I need help.
我不...知道怎么...办
I don't-- I don't know how to-- how to do this
也不知道这种情况该怎样或是否有用 但...
or how it works or if it works, but--
我...知道我不能失去她
I-- I know I can't lose her.
所以...求求你 上帝 听到我的祈祷
So-- So, please, God, hear me pray.
通常会让大家单独待一会儿
Like to give everyone a little alone time in here
看看会发生什么 一般有罪的人都会睡着
to see what happens. Guilty ones tend to fall asleep.
我不可能
No chance with that.
我是无辜的 并且肾上腺飙升 极度焦虑
I'm innocent and wired on adrenaline and anxiety.
我最喜欢嫌犯一上来就说自己是无辜的
Love it when a suspect tells me they're innocent right off the bat.
感觉特别可信
It feels so believable.
嫌犯 我以为我是目击者
Suspect? I thought I was a witness.
古德曼先生
So, Mr. Goodman,
为什么我们会发现你在现场 身上是血迹
how'd it happen that we found you covered in blood,
兜里有毒品
bag of dope in your pocket,
站在一个头上有弹孔的女孩旁
standing over a girl with a hole in her head?
如果你这么形容...
When you put it that way...
在开始前 我必须问...
Before we start, I have to ask--
- 当然 你想要律师吗  - 不是问我的事
- Sure, do you want a lawyer? - Not about me.
那女孩 她...会活下去吗
The girl. She-- She going to live?
我不确定 听上去不乐观
I'm not sure. Doesn't sound great.
如果你有宗教信仰 我本人是没有 我认为 是时候祷告了
If you're a religious man, which I am not, I'd say now is the time to pray.
好的
Okay--
杨先生
Mr. Yeung.
麦克法登警探 曼哈顿北区凶案组
Detective McFadden, Manhattan North Homicide.
我是负责你女儿一案的警探之一
I'm one of the detectives working your daughter's case.
凶杀  可是...她还活着
Homicide? But-- But she isn't dead.
不
No.
但是 你知道 如果发生了什么
But, you know, if anything changes,
我们只想确保没有漏掉任何细节
we just want to make sure we didn't miss something.
你知道 这种情况下派来的警探更优秀
You know, you get a much better class of detective this way.
相信我 你不希望这起案件 由暴力犯罪组的那些小丑来负责
And believe me, you don't want this handled by the jokers in violent crime.
我知道这是艰难的时刻
Now, I know this is a difficult time,
但你介意我问你几个问题吗
but do you mind if I ask you a few questions?
外套里有半克海洛因
Half a gram of heroin in that jacket.
我猜你是买 不是卖
I'm assuming you were buying, not selling?
什么 两个都没有
What? No, neither.
正如我说的 那不是我的外套 我从不吸毒
Like I said, it wasn't my suit, and I've never done drugs.
从不
Never?
好的 我吸过大麻 其实今晚吸过
Okay. Well, I have smoked pot. Tonight, actually.
- 等等 所以你在公园时是嗑嗨状态  - 天啊
- Wait, so you were high in the park? - My goodness.
不 我几乎没吸入 我只是想让别人觉得我有趣
No. I barely even inhaled. I just wanted to seem like I was fun.
我之前在一个派对 是哈密尔顿斯维尼家的人举办的
I was at a party, hosted by the Hamilton-Sweeneys.
也许你听过他们
Maybe you've heard of them.
没什么印象
Doesn't ring a bell.
我的室友威廉 他的父亲是派对主人
My roommate, William, his father was the host,
不过他不在场
though he wasn't there.
威廉也不在 他和他们疏远了
Neither was William. He's estranged from them now.
我没有高档外套可以穿去那样的派对
I didn't have a suit nice enough to wear to a party like that.
邀请函要求夏季白色服装
Summer whites, the invitation said.
所以我...借了威廉的
So I-- I borrowed William's.
所以是他的外套 他的海洛因
So his jacket, his heroin.
你知道他有这个习惯
Were you aware of his habit?
他说过已经戒掉了
He told me it was in the past.
我很愚蠢地相信了他
Foolishly, I believed him.
瘾君子有这种本领 他们撒起谎来不打草稿
Addicts have that way about them. They lie as easy as they breathe.
但我没有撒谎
But I am not a liar.
我说过了 我在等巴士
It is like I told you, I was waiting for the bus.
她在等别的什么车或什么人
She was waiting for something or someone else.
我回来时 她不见了
When I got back, she was gone.
我循着声音走进公园
When I followed that sound into the park,
我...发现了她 我就向你们报警了
I-- I found her, and I called you.
好的
Okay.
那么我们就假设 你是个在错的时间出现的热心群众
Let's say you're just a Good Samaritan with lousy timing.
不意味着你就洗脱嫌疑了
It doesn't mean you're off the hook just yet.
我们已经鉴定了你的弹药残留物 我们还要采集你的指纹
You've been dusted for gunpowder residue and obliged us a set of fingerprints.
你也得留下电话号码和地址
I'm also gonna need your phone number and your address.
别说谎 我会核实的
Do not lie. I will be checking.
你不能离开城市 在结案前
And you don't leave the city. Till this case is solved,
你将一直是谋杀未遂案的
you will continue to be a person of interest
嫌疑人
in an attempted murder.
谢谢你 帕尔撒警探
Thank you, Detective Parsa.
我希望你们找到真凶
And I hope you find who did it.
我只和她简短地聊了聊
I only spoke to her briefly,
但是感觉她是个生活丰富多彩的女孩
but she seemed like a girl with so much to live for.
孩子 起床了 早上好
Son, wake up. Well, good morning.
老天爷
Jesus Christ.
抱歉 我不该在这里 我不属于这里 抱歉
Sorry. I shouldn't be here. I don't belong here. I'm sorry.
这是上帝的地方 任何人都属于这里
This is God's house. Everyone belongs here.
我们甚至不会锁门
We don't even lock the door.
我是犹太教的
Well, I'm Jewish.
我是被领养的 但...
I'm adopted, but--
我父母和我说了这事后 我嘴里冒出来的第一句话是
Well, the first thing I said when my parents told me was,
“我不是被选择的 ” 他们说:“你是 查理 我们选择了你”
"So, I'm not chosen?" And they said, "You are, Charlie, by us."
你知道
And, you know,
这话无意冒犯长岛花山的威斯巴格一家
no offense to the Weisbargers of Flower Hill, Long Island,
但是从圣经的角度而言 这不是同一个概念
but, like, biblically speaking, that's not really the same thing.
孩子 你为什么来这里
What's brought you here, son?
发生了一件可怕的事 而我不知道该怎么办
Something terrible happened, and I don't really know what to do.
我想知道她是否平安无事 但一部分的我不想知道
I wanna know if she's okay, but part of me wants to not know
只想保持不知道的状态 因为如果她出事了 那我...
and wants to keep not knowing, because if she's not, then I--
我不知道自己会做出什么事
I don't really know what I'll do.
如果她...
Like, if she--
如果她没能存活 那我也无法活下去
If she does not survive, then I will not survive.
你...明白吗
Does that-- Does that make any sense?
我很抱歉 太难解释了
I'm sorry. It's too much to explain.
凯特 你能把声音调小吗
Cate, can you turn that down?
太大声了 我犯头痛了
It's really loud. It's giving me a headache.
也可能是因为你宿醉
Or you're really hungover.
你怎么知道那是什么
How do you even know what that is?
所以你承认啦
So, you admit it?
我什么都没承认
I admit nothing.
抱歉让你久等 蕾根
Sorry for the wait, Regan.
你父亲在睡觉 我不想打扰他
Your father is sleeping, and I really don't want to disturb him.
- 我们还要赶航班 - 好的
- We've got the flight ahead of us. - Okay,
但那正是我打给你的原因
but that's why I'm calling.
艾莫里或菲莉希亚和他聊过吗
Did Amory or Felicia speak with him?
因为他在落地前需要知道一些事
Because there are some things he needs to know before he lands.
他们没有 医生也警告过 不要有不必要的压力
They haven't. And the doctors warned against unnecessary stress.
好的 但只可惜 这次的压力是必要的
Okay, but unfortunately, this stress is necessary,
他能消化这消息的时间越多 就越好 你能不能叫醒他
and the more time he has to process it, the better. So, if you could just wake him
让他听电话 我会很感激
and put him on the phone, I'd really appreciate that.
抱歉 蕾根 我不会这么做 你可以在他回家后和他聊
I'm sorry, Regan. I'm not gonna do that. You can talk to him when he's home.
他挂我电话 这混蛋挂我电话
He hung up on me. The fucker hung up on me.
别盯着我看
Redirect those eyeballs somewhere else.
我以为你在和我说话
I thought you were talking to me.
- 你还和谁在聊  - 等等 威尔 等一下
- Who else were you talking to? - Hold on, Will. Hold on.
嘿 是的 抱歉 我不能...
Hey. Yes. Sorry, I-- I couldn't--
我昨晚没去派对 我有些事
I didn't make it to the party last night. Something came up.
不需要解释 你是个懦夫 我懂
No need for an explanation. You're a coward, I get it.
我真希望我能打给世界上其他任何一个人
And I wish I had literally anyone else in the world to call.
但我父亲今天从妙佑诊所回来时
But when my father gets back from the Mayo Clinic today,
他会被直接带到法官室接受审问
he's going to be taken directly to the judge's chamber to be arraigned.
什么
What?
- 指控是什么  - 电信诈骗
- What's the charge? - Wire fraud.
什么...那...是联邦罪行
What-- That's a-- That's a federal offense.
对 显然他可能被判20年监禁
Yeah. Apparently, it can get you 20 years in prison.
而且第五大道房产的贷款也要到期了
Not to mention we have loans coming due on the 5th Avenue buildings.
所以 如果银行不愿与我们做生意 那我们会失去一切
So, if the banks won't do business with us, well, we could lose everything.
蕾根 你的父亲绝不会 做任何不诚信的事情
Regan, your father would never do anything dishonest.
显然 不是故意做 像...
Well, obviously-- Not on purpose, like--
你知道我有多兢兢业业 但如果...
You know how diligent I've been, but if--
我无法看完他签过名的每一份文件
I can't look at every document that has his signature on it.
我甚至不知道他是否知道任何情况
I'm not even sure if he knows anything about it,
他可能完全不知情
or if he's gonna be totally blindsided.
艾莫里怎么想
What does Amory think?
要是我知道就好了 我联系不上他
I wish I knew. I can't get a hold of him.
一位律师给我留言说 一切都处理好了
I got a message through a lawyer that said everything had been taken care of
我应该留在家里 但我...不能这么做
and I should just stay home, and I-- I can't do that.
所以...总之 我知道今天不是轮到你 但如果你可以...让孩子...
So-- Anyway, I know it's not your day, but if you could-- The kids could just--
天啊 当然我会照顾他们 这是我至少该做的
Oh, my God. Yeah, of course I'll take 'em. It's the least I could do.
是 可不是嘛
Well, yeah. No shit.
不过得说 今天我状态不太好
Gotta say, they're not exactly getting me at my best.
不会比我更糟糕
Can't be worse than I am right now.
在我记忆里 你喝醉后都是优雅的
I've never known you to be anything other than an elegant drunk.
尽快过来 好吗
Just get here as soon as you can, okay?
好的...
Yeah, yeah.
该死的
Fuck.
- 帕尔撒 - 麦克法登
- Parsa. - McFadden.
警探 有什么消息
Detective, what's the latest?
你应该了解我的一点是 我最讨厌医院
One thing you should know about me, I fucking hate hospitals.
是...谁会喜欢 那女孩情况如何
Yeah, yeah. Who doesn't? How's the girl?
活着
Alive.
- 父亲呢  - 崩溃了
- And the father? - A wreck.
萨曼莎是他的一切
Samantha's his whole life.
老婆在小萨11岁时离开 和一个瑜伽老师搬到加州
Wife left when Sam was 11, moved to California with a yoga instructor.
从此杳无音讯 够冷酷的
Never heard from her again. Brutal.
关于她在公园做什么 他有没有任何想法
Did he have any thoughts on what she was doing in the park?
没有 萨曼莎是个好学生
No. Samantha was a good student.
拿奖学金进了纽约大学 但她在城里有精彩的生活
Got into NYU on scholarship, but she's got a big life in the city,
她的父亲有自己的问题
and her father has his own problems.
据说他制作烟花 但生意不好
Apparently, he makes fireworks, but business isn't so good.
烟花啊
Fireworks, huh?
小萨是摄影师 作家 喜欢城中心俱乐部的新音乐
Sam's a photographer, a writer, into new music in downtown clubs.
我要在第八大道和大学广场街的路口下车
I'm getting dropped at 8th and University Place.
- 来找我吧 - 为什么
- Come meet me. - Why?
那里是她的宿舍 她有室友
It's her dorm. Has a roommate.
是 好的 那里见
Yeah, okay. I'll see you there.
天啊 怎么回事
Jesus. What the fuck?
嗨
Hi.
那是血吗
Is that blood?
- 是的 这是血 - 你还好吗
- Yes. This is blood. - You okay?
这不是我的血 如果你是问这个的话
It's not my blood if that's what you're asking.
但如果你只是普通问候 那么 不 我不好
But if you're just wondering in a more general sense, no, I'm not okay.
天啊 墨瑟
Jesus, Merce.
是这样 昨晚我去了 汉密尔顿斯维尼的国庆日嘉年华派对
See, last night, I went to the Hamilton-Sweeney Fourth of July gala.
你父亲没去 但我见到了恶魔弟弟
See, your father couldn't make it, but I did meet the demon uncle.
很理解为什么给他起这个绰号
Totally get the nickname.
但昨晚真正有趣的部分是之后
But the really interesting part of the night was later,
我在公园发现一个女孩 她的头部中枪了
when I had found a girl in the park who had been shot in the head.
我作为她的谋杀未遂案嫌疑人被警察拘留
I was then taken into custody as a suspect in her attempted murder.
等等...你认真的
Stop... You're serious?
警察怎么可能觉得你枪击某人
How could the cops possibly think that you shot someone?
90%是种族歧视
I'd say 90% racism
10%是他们发现的半克海洛因
and 10% the half-gram of heroin that they found
- 在你美丽的西服外套口袋里 - 好吧
- in the pocket of your lovely suit jacket... - Okay.
他们扣留了 因为那成了证据
...which they kept because it is now evidence.
听着 关于你昨晚的经历 我很抱歉
Look, I am really sorry about your night
但也不是我把我的毒品放在你的外套里
but it's not like I kept my drugs in your jacket.
而且我好几年没穿过那件该死的西服了
Plus, I haven't worn that fucking suit in years.
你上周才穿去米涅塔酒馆吃晚餐
You wore it for dinner at Minetta Tavern last week!
威廉 你说你会戒掉海洛因
William, you told me you would quit using heroin!
这是我搬来和你同居的条件
It was a condition of my moving in with you!
是 “成瘾”不是平白无故叫的 对吧
Yeah. Well, they don't call it addiction for nothing?
听着 要不是你背着我去那个派对
I mean, look. If you would have just not gone to that party behind my back,
那这一切都不会发生
then none of this would've happened.
所以你要另开一个话题争吵
So, you're going to start a different fight,
就不用继续这个话题了
so we don't have to finish this one?
你总是在被逼入绝境后推卸责任
You always turn tables when you're cornered!
我不喜欢被逼入绝境
I don't like being cornered.
我希望你和我一起去
I wanted you to come with me.
不 墨瑟 听我说 好吗 我不想去
No. Mercer, listen to me, okay? I didn't want to go.
那是我的家人 那是我的邀请函
That's my family. That's my invitation.
我的西服 我该死的海洛因
My suit, my fucking heroin.
如果...
And if-- if--
如果你可以不要一天到晚关注我...
if you could just stop being so interested in me all the time--
我去哪 我在做什么 我来自哪
Where I go, what I'm doing, where I come from,
我朝血管里注射什么... 我们本可拥有美好生活
what I fucking inject into my veins-- We could have a beautiful life.
这就是...为什么我什么都没和你说
This is-- This is exactly why I didn't fucking say anything to you,
因为...我知道你有多么爱批判人
because-- because I know how judgmental you can be.
- 我不...我不是在批判你 - 不是吗
- I'm not-- No, I'm not judging you. - No?
- 威廉 我开始担心... - 好吧
- William, I am growing concerned... - Okay.
你的健康 这会影响我们的关系
...for your health, for our relationship!
我们的关系 好吧
Our relationship. All right.
那我问你个问题 你为什么对这事大惊小怪
Let me ask you a question. How can you make such a big deal
而你此前都不知道这事的存在
out of something that you didn't even know was happening?
不
No.
这逻辑太扭曲
That is some twisted logic.
该死 你真的是个艺术家
Damn, you-- you really are an artist.
是 也许如果你更有创造力 你就会理解
Yeah, well, maybe if you were more creative, you would understand.
知道吗 我此刻感到一股创造力在迸发
You know what? I am feeling a burst of creativity coming out of me.
你真的要半途离开
Are you seriously walking out?
对 是的 真的
No, yeah, I seriously am.
你...就站在那里 当真
You're-- You're just going to stand there? Really?
怎么 你觉得我挪不动你
What, you don't think that I can move you?
- 你来试啊... - 真的
- You can try... - Seriously?
但我希望你不会
...but I'm hoping that you won't.
好 像木板一样坚硬 像石头一样强大...
Okay. Stiff as a board, strong as a rock. Stiff as a board, strong as--
对不起
I'm sorry.
我只是太累了
I'm just so tired.
我知道
I know you are.
这是一种病
It's a sickness.
我知道
I know it is.
嘿
Hey.
请别放弃我
Please don't give up on me.
妈咪...
Mommy, Mommy!
凯特 宝贝 怎么了
Cate, honey, what is it?
我们昨晚见到的蓝色小鸟死了
The blue bird we saw last night, it's dead.
好的 别碰它 身上都是细菌
Okay. Don't touch it. It's full of germs.
大概没有 它还没发出臭气或引来苍蝇
Doubtful. It's barely starting to smell or draw flies,
所以死亡时间不长
so it hasn't been dead that long.
好的 鸟类犯罪现场调查专家
Okay, avian crime scene investigator.
你确定它是死了 而不是在睡觉吗
Are you sure it's dead and not just sleeping?
非常确定 它中枪了
Quite sure. It's been shot.
中枪
Shot?
你看这里 肚子上有干净 穿透的伤口
Look here. A clean through-and-through wound to its belly.
谁会朝美丽的小鸟开枪
Who would shoot a beautiful bird?
我...不知道 宝贝 但我们最好处理掉它
I-- I don't know, honey, but we should probably get rid of it.
威尔 你能不能找个盒子什么的  我们把它放进去
Will, can you get, like, a box or something that we can put it in?
妈 这只是一只愚蠢的死鸟 不需要给它举办葬礼
It's just a dumb, dead bird, Mom. It doesn't need a funeral.
需要 我要找一朵花
Yes, it does. I'm going to find a flower.
拜托了 任何东西 报纸...
Please? Anything, a newspaper--
这样我不用碰它
Just so I don't have to touch it.
布鲁克林为什么会有鹦鹉
What is a parrot doing in Brooklyn?
这不是鹦鹉 是蓝蕉鹃
It's not a parrot. It's a great blue turaco.
可能是从布朗克斯动物园的 鸟类世界逃出来的
Probably escaped from the World of Birds at the Bronx Zoo.
- 你多大  - 十岁
- How old are you? - Ten.
威尔12岁
Will's 12.
他以前和你一样
He used to be like you.
对世界充满兴趣 你懂吗
Interested in things, you know?
谢谢
Thank you.
- 那是他吗 威尔  - 对
- That him? Will? - Yeah.
嘿 威尔 你知道 金星是唯一顺时针自转的行星吗
Hey, Will. Did you know Venus is the only planet that spins clockwise?
好吧
Okay.
嘿 我好想你
Hey. I've missed you.
这是什么 花
What's this? A flower?
(少女受害者头部中枪)
- 给我的吗  - 对
- Is that for me? - Yes.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hey. - Hi.
怎么 不说“谢谢”呀
What, no "thank you?"
我...开玩笑的 天啊 别生气
I'm-- I'm kidding, I'm kidding. Jesus. Come-- Come on.
- 威尔在那边 - 嘿 伙计
- Will's over there. - Hey, champ.
他怎么了
What's with him?
他不一直这样
What is it ever?
嘿 你爸今天到
Hey. Your dad's getting in today,
- 所以他昨晚不在  - 对
- so he wasn't there last night? - No.
- 所以你没和他聊  - 还没有
- So, you didn't talk to him? - Not yet.
好了 各位 我们做什么呢
All right, guys. What are we gonna do?
老天
Jesus.
查尔斯
Charles,
- 你在哪  - 我在这里
- where are you? - I'm here.
小萨 醒醒 小萨 拜托
Sam, wake up. Sam, come on, please.
- 嘿 - 嗨
- Hey. - Hi.
嗨 我以为你午饭后才来
Hi. I wasn't expecting you till after lunch.
把牛奶给我 谢谢
Pass me the milk, please?
是 没问题
Yeah, of course.
在米奇那里一切可好
Everything okay at Mickey's?
是...很好 我只是...
Yeah, yeah, fine. I just--
我只是早起然后感到无聊 所以我...就回家了
I just woke up early and got bored, so I-- I came home.
明白
Okay.
我能拿走这个吗
Can I take this?
(中央公园枪击案影响了国庆烟花表演)
(没有线索)
(枪击案后48小时 成为悬案)
(新年前夕在等待 爱你的小萨)
(纽约大学 兰兹曼宿舍)
知道我们确切的目的地
Know exactly where we're going?
我们需要和这里的谁聊
Who we need to talk to here?
我压根不知道怎么在大学宿舍找路
Hell if I know how a college dorm works.
我当时住在家里 在莫霍克谷社区学院拿了45个学分就滚了
I lived at home, got my 45 credits from Mohawk Valley and split.
我们找到负责人 然后找她的房间吧
Guess we find someone in charge and find her room.
是 好吧
Yeah, all right.
谢谢
Thank you.
(在此给莱拉和小萨留言)
(嗨 莱拉 下午2点 去公园的植物园找我们)
- 出了什么事  - 谁说出事了
- What happened? - Who said something happened?
我们能进来问你几个问题吗
May we come in and ask you some questions, please?
好的
Yeah.
你最后一次见到萨曼莎是什么时候
When was the last time you saw Samantha?
两周前吧
Two weeks, maybe?
我们俩都决定暑假留在宿舍 但她来来去去
We both decided to stay for the summer, but she comes and goes.
我在图书馆当实习生 所以我工作日不在
I've got an internship at the library, so I'm gone weekdays.
她大多夜晚和周末都不在
She's gone most nights and weekends.
是吗 她去哪了
Yeah? Where does she go?
我从没被邀请过
Not that I've ever been invited,
但她去看很多音乐会
but she goes to a lot of music shows.
她的朋友是乐队的人
Her friends are in some band.
你是否记得乐队名字
Do you remember the name of the band?
我从没听说过他们 但名字是拉丁文
I've never heard of them, but it's Latin.
类似“活在当下” 但不是这句
It's-- It's like carpe diem, but not.
她在这里没什么个人物品
She doesn't have much here.
她一开始有比较多
She started with more
但越来越少 现在她基本不在这里过夜了
but it just got less and less, and now she barely sleeps here.
你觉得她在哪里过夜
Well, where do you think she's sleeping?
她是否曾提到任何特别的人
I mean, she ever mention anybody special?
没有 但是她不怎么和我说自己的事
No, but she doesn't tell me a lot.
小萨做了什么吗
Did Sam do something?
(纽约大学)
You think there's anything to this music angle?
你觉得这个音乐爱好方面是否会有线索
我是说 我们只有这唯一的切入口 所以 会
I mean, it's the only angle we have. So, sure.
熊猫女孩问小萨是否犯了什么事
Panda Girl asked if Sam was guilty of something,
而不是问她是不是受害者 这反映了她的个人喜好
not if she was a victim. That says something about what she was into.
也可能反映了熊猫女孩的内心 要我说 她挺爱评判人的
Or it says something about Panda Girl. Kind of judgy, if you ask me.
嗨
Hey.
是...我在路上了
Yeah, yeah. On my way.
你有老婆
You got a wife?
现在还有 你呢
For now. What about you?
我呢 怎么 我有没有老婆
What about me? What, do I have a wife?
对 不 电话上的不是我老婆 那是犯罪现场组
Yeah, no, that wasn't my wife. That was CSU.
他们在犯罪现场准备好了
They're ready at the crime scene.
菲莉希亚 不如你先去车上 我马上就过去
Felicia, why don't you go to the car? I'll be just a minute.
比尔很快就落地 我们不能迟到
Bill lands shortly. We can't be late.
我保证你的脸将会是他最先看到的脸
I promise yours will be the first face he sees.
昨晚公园的事真是见不得光 很悲惨
Sordid business in the park last night. Tragic.
据说是个年轻女孩 什么样的禽兽...
Apparently, she was a young girl. What kind of animal--
对了 我很好奇
By the way, I was curious,
吉斯兰普莱特有去派对吗
did Keith Lamplighter ever show up at the party?
我不记得见过他
Yeah, I don't remember seeing him.
让我查查
Let me check.
对 他似乎没到场
Yeah, looks like he didn't show.
不知道他因为什么事无法到场
I wonder what would have kept him away.
也许他有更好的活动 祝你愉快
I guess he got a better offer. Have a good one.
爸爸...
Daddy! Daddy! Daddy!
(联邦调查局)
- 嗨 - 蕾根 宝贝
- Hi! - Regan, honey!
听着 我不知道...别人对你说了什么
Listen, I don't know what-- what people have told you,
但我们必须和这些人一起走
but we're going to have to go with these men.
他必须独自走 你可以跟在后面
He's coming alone. You can follow.
- 等等 你们要给他铐手铐  - 怎么回事 我不...
- Wait, are you fucking cuffing him? - What's happening? I don't--
怎么 你们觉得他会逃跑
What, do you think he's gonna flee?
无论是什么情况 我是清白的
Whatever this is, I'm innocent.
对 我知道 你当然是
Yeah, I know. Of course you are,
他们...我们...必须想办法
and they're-- And we're-- we're gonna have to figure this out,
但这需要一些程序
but it's gonna be a process.
不 我是在问 这是个...问题
No, I mean, I'm asking. It's a-- It's a question.
我能和他一起去吗 拜托  我可以解释一切
Can I go with him, please? So that I can explain everything?
我们可以解释
We can explain.
我们到那边见 亲爱的
We'll see you there, darling.
你们能对他轻一点吗
Can you be careful with him?
你知道他们要给他铐手铐
You knew they were gonna cuff him.
我们不得不做出一些妥协
We had to make some compromises.
他们同意进行私下审问
They agreed to this private arraignment
这样就不用在周末把他拘留在“陵墓”
so they didn't have to hold him in the Tombs for the weekend.
他们给他戴手铐 给老人铐手铐 你真是失心疯了
They cuffed him. They handcuffed an old man. You're fucking insane!
听着 我知道你很沮丧
Look, I know you're upset.
(警方戒严线 不得跨越)
- How's it looking? - No one knows better than you.
- 情况如何  - 没有新发现
公园犯罪总是很难调查 人流量大 还有垃圾 枯叶
Park is always tough. Lots of traffic, trash and leaf litter.
这边有发现
Think we got something!
这是个很棒的发现 可惜是对其他人的案子来说
That's a great find, for somebody else's case.
那玩意看上去有20年了
That thing looks 20 years old,
而且我们的受害者 是被.38口径而不是.45口径的枪射中
not to mention our vic was shot with a .38, not a .45.
我去散散步
I'm gonna go for a walk.
嘿 拯救城市 布鲁伯格去死
Hey! Save the city. Fuck Bloomberg.
有人吗
Hello?
嘿 混蛋 这有点太过了
Hey, asshole. That's just a little too much.
别这么孬种
Don't be a little bitch.
抱歉 但我不想死
Sorry if I don't wanna die.
- 你不会死的 - 行吧 失去一只手
- You're not gonna die. - Fine. Lose a fucking hand.
别说了 把那玩意点着 快
Stop talking and just light that thing already. Come on.
抱歉打扰 但是 你们...
Sorry to interrupt, but you guys--
搞什么鬼 谁让你进来的
What the fuck? Who the fuck let you in here?
- 查理 你为什么来  - 哟 哥们 放掉
- Charlie? What are you doing here? - Yo, dude, drop it.
快放掉 该死
Drop it now! Fuck!
成功了
It fucking worked.
It fucking worked!
真美
That was beautiful.
- 尼基 你搞什么  - 哟 成功了...
- What the fuck, Nicky? - Yo, it fucking worked. It fucking worked.
天啊
Jesus.
- 不该让你看见的 - 嘿 索尔 别
- You shouldn't have seen that. - Hey, Sol, don't.
我可以解释 我来...
I can explain. I came--
让我猜猜 你有新案子了
Let me guess. You caught a new case.
对 谋杀未遂 公园里的少女
Yeah. Attempted murder. Teenage girl in the park.
某个混蛋对准她的颅骨开了一枪
Some son of a bitch put one right in her skull.
天 现在的人都有什么毛病
Oh, my God. What's wrong with people?
嘿 我得挂了
Hey, I gotta go.
恶心 真臭
Fuck. Fucking stinks.
嘿 有发现吗
Hey, you got something?
这看起来是拉丁文吗
Does this look like Latin to you?
活在当下啊
Carpe fucking diem.
字幕翻译:易晗